I got tired of waiting.
Waiting for this time and place.
Who are you?
I told you, didn't I?
I said you were me, and I was you.
I welcome you.
The one who clung to the mercy of his loved one,
erased his own memories, and ran away has returned.
Stop it.
What do you mean?
Re-l Mayer,
your role ends here.
The rest of the show is for him and me.
Foolish defect...
Daedalus!
What is he doing?
I whispered the prepared scenario for when
the time came for the dome's destruction to him.
It seems his destructive impulses have also been awakened...
just as ours had.
It's futile!
Accede to fate.
Even if you people survive, you can't be the winners.
Even so, I will not run away from the
reality of what is happening right now.
Even if an even harsher reality awaits...
I will do what I must. I will come back, no matter what.
That's a promise, Vincent.
Re-l...
You complete my fate
The world unwinds inside of me
The halo crawls away
You refill my place
Come and save me
Believe in me and drink the wine and take my hand and fill me up
Golo presents
Come and save me
Re-l.
Now, take a good look.
That's what you look like.
That mask you wear is the shape of
the soul of one who has escaped fate.
Let's confirm this again:
Have you really erased your memories?
Did you even have those memories in the first place?
Perhaps you are merely a fool entrapped with
the notion that his memories have been erased.
In the end, you know nothing...
Am I wrong?
You're wrong!
The journey... That in itself was necessary.
I perceived the steady recovery of nature from destruction
with all of my senses, and felt it with my heart.
If I had not done that, I wouldn't have wanted to return here.
It is indeed true that, while it nurtures,
neither the cradle nor the ark educates.
And the experience of facing the world by
oneself would drastically change one's views.
It seems you did receive my message, then.
Answer me!
What are we...
What are PROXIES?
PROXIES - just interpret the name literally.
We are the Creator's proxies.
The Creator...
meditation  proxy
Vincent...
And then... I understood all of it.
Where are you?
I understood all of the malice the Creator wrought.
After prolonged suffering, I finally fulfilled my duty as a proxy.
The moment I succeeded in reviving
humanity, the changes in my body began.
That was the heartbeat of beginning...
the commencement of the PROXY destruction program.
Then... you took humanity and...
However, we cannot fight the program.
An extremely reasonable system...
How ironic.
Even though PROXIES are messengers
of God, once they fulfill their mission,
they are unnecessary elements that are left
behind after humanity is led to the Promised Land.
Worse, they are merely monsters... demons.
But even the ark, which according to
that plan was to have been abandoned,
had developed a soul...
Why...
Why did the Creator give us souls?
If we did not have souls, we wouldn't suffer...
You must know why.
Yes...
I have no need for an answer.
We came to understand through our own efforts.
We were worshipped, betrayed, and brought to despair
by the defective humans we created.
And yet we still love them.
The Creator must have wanted to be loved as well,
just as we savored their love in our solitude.
And that is why we must punish them.
What can we possibly do now?
If you've rebuilt humanity as they've desired...
Did you come to a realization, Vincent
Law, you who have forgotten everything?
That is proof that you are an entrapped shadow.
I manipulated you,
caused emotions to take root in the defects,
and re-annihilated the newly resurrected humanity...
Then, humanity has been...
The shadow will know
the fate of those who were punished
for desiring God in a godless world.
Humanity was meant to perish,
for they led the world to destruction and then fled,
just as you fled Romdeau, the world that you created.
Vincent Law is the afterimage of
PROXY One who was taken by despair.
No. He is merely the doppelgänger left behind by Ergo PROXY, a fake.
A fake...
However, a well-made fake.
Think about it.
You also despaired and left this place.
You fled from everything.
You and I... we are the same.
Shut up!
Then fight!
Number five and number eight have been silenced.
All of the dome's backup power sources have been killed.
The destruction cannot be stopped.
Daedalus.
That's right!
Obey your instincts!
Liberate yourself!
I can understand!
Understand the sadness of having
your insignificant existence rejected.
I don't care who I was before I became who I am.
But I am just myself.
That is the only truth!
Indeed, there is only one truth.
We tear apart the message entrusted by a
selfish race who destroyed themselves, then run away.
Isn't that who we are?
You are right.
You and I are Ergo PROXY,
PROXY One.
We have been abandoned.
It is meaningless.
You haven't changed at all.
You make me sick.
Don't you get it?
Both this play and our roles in it have ended.
Romdeau is finished.
And defective citizens can only disappear.
That's not true.
There must be something we can still do!
No, this is the end.
Besides, what difference can we,
pseudo-humans, make in the battle between gods?
As mere cogs in the wheel, we can be silent.
Yes, like Donov.
What Grandfather desired... A meeting with the Creator...
Even if that was the reason why I was born, I didn't care.
I have always wanted to love
Grandfather from the bottom of my heart.
I wanted to feel that I was loved.
I just wanted to be loved.
But the Administrator rejected even that.
He's the same.
He only opened his heart to Vincent Law... no, to Ergo PROXY.
You're the same too.
I...
Daedalus.
Too bad.
PROXIES can't live under a blue sky.
Their amrita cells do not permit that.
What do you mean?
They, too, are beings meant to be eradicated from this world.
So that's where you were, my beloved!
Re-l-2, Real!
Wonderful...
She is complete!
I created a god!
Come, Re-l...
Come for me.
Not that way.
Don't go!
Why does Re-l always leave me behind?
Please don't go.
Daedalus!
But you are not Vincent Law!
Why hesitate over a fake created by defects?
And what can you possibly know?
I know.
I already told you...
I am...
You, right?
That's why I came back...
to kill me!
What must be saved isn't the world!
Over there!
But what would that change?
Continuing to kill wouldn't-
Please stop!
The PROXIES' role is finished!
You again...
Monad.
Monad...
I've finally found you.
I've been looking... for you.
Don't interfere, Monad.
It is true that the proxies' role is finished.
And... the humanity I resurrected has been destroyed.
The immortal "winner" will also be destroyed.
This was also part of your plan?
This is my revenge.
The rest is up to you.
That will be... your world.
You...
You're going to burden me with everything again?
You don't have to save a world like this!
I know.
I know you can't do that.
So it's all right now.
Stop, Monad.
It's over for everyone!
I don't want to see anyone grieve anymore.
Monad...
Are you going to run away again?
Don't listen to anyone.
Close your sacred eyes.
Please stop, Monad.
That's right.
They were all told not to listen to the PROXY.
But I want to help Vince.
I wonder why I'm different from everybody.
There's nothing different about you.
Kristeva.
When they say cogito has created a fledgling self...
it means someone is following their own will.
It doesn't mean you have to ignore PROXIES.
You hear it too?
You just need to do what your heart tells you.
Where's my Papa?
He told me to give this to you.
Let's hurry, Pino.
Yep!
Cogito was built into the PROXY Plan.
It was mankind's safety valve.
Autoreivs were just part of the PROXY Plan.
Their revolt helped bring about the plan's ruin.
That's enough, Daedalus.
In other words...
bringing back the human race through
the PROXY project wasn't the first option.
Everything here right now is an obstacle to the first option.
That includes you and me.
Despite all our pain...
and love...
even our souls are...
Daedalus...
Go, Re-l.
There's still a truth you have to face, isn't there?
That gave me trouble...
but you're my favorite, Re-l.
Daedalus.
You don't have much time.
Go straight through here...
follow the maintenance rail and you'll come to the plug vent.
Hurry.
I'm sorry, Daedalus.
I'm sick and tired of hearing you say that, Re-l.
I'd better go, Daedalus.
Yes.
Run, Re-l!
That's it.
What is this light?
It is holy.
A portent of rebirth.
The sun...
I'm sure.
Yes,
a true blue sky will spread as far as the eye can see...
shining and beautiful forever.
So you don't have to worry about anything anymore.
Yes...
Wait.
What's wrong?
Why do you look sad?
Forget everything.
I'm sorry.
Why?
I must no longer forget.
It's not about duties or fate.
Facing each other. Fighting each other.
Supporting each other. Holding each other.
We live on.
What is good about that reality?
A reality so dark... cold... and with such an uncertain future.
But that...
is our reality.
Even in a world like that, someone is waiting for me.
It's her, isn't it.
I'll return this to you, Monad.
Vincent...
Goodbye, Real.
Goodbye, my beloved.
No, don't fly so high.
Ah, the world is so beautiful.
And yet...
which sky should I seek?
I can hear it.
"The plan"...
"Transition."
So it was you...
who was calling.
Vincent...
In the end, the future you chose is...
Let us welcome the Creator.
D-Don't...
But in that sky... you'll...
So you returned.
Yes.
Vincent Law,
you are truly a shadow.
The shadow has defeated me, an immortal,
and broken the shackles of the heartbeat.
And that was also the liberation of the imperfect ones you loved.
That's right.
A woman who can see into the future...
She is indeed your - Vincent Law's - reality.
The sun will return.
Our world will end.
However...
Live, Vincent.
Your survival will be the Creator's punishment.
Dammit.
After coming this far...
Dammit...
Is this it?
Re-l-Re-l!
Pino!
I have faith.
You're Raul's...
Protecting Pino...
It was the last duty as an Entourage that he charged me with.
She found this for me too.
Is Vincent...
Don't worry.
I can hear his voice.
I can see Vince.
Distance: 1107 units!
What a troublemaker.
I guess we'll have to go get him.
Yeah!
This world is the reality we face.
But I...
will face this world with Re-l and the others who have survived.
Now that man has returned for the
first time in several thousand years
to a land that nears complete revival,
the true battle will begin.
I am Ergo PROXY...
the proxy of death.
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
Please
could
you
stop
the
noise,
I'm
trying
to
get
some
rest
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
From
all
the
un
born
chic
head
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
What's
that...?
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid
I
may
be
para
noid,
but
not
an
droid